Peter Torr **Smith**

mobile, web & cloud product technologist, developer, analyst, delivery

Wellington

phone: +64-21-451967

NZ Citizen

email: peter@ptorrsmith.com

web: ptorrsmith.com

github: github.com/ptorrsmith linkedln: linkedin.com/in/ptorrsmith

SKILLS BRIEF

➤ Full-stack ➤ Ruby, Rails ➤ React ➤ Javascript/Typescript ➤ DBs, APIs, Data ➤ Node.js / Express

- ➤ AWS, Cloud, DevOps, Pipelines ➤ Git / Github / Bitbucket ➤ HTML, CSS ➤ Bootstrap ➤ Hubspot APIs
- ➤ Stripe payments ➤ Architecture ➤ Wireframing / flow / Design ➤ Business & UX Analysis ➤ SaaS
- > Project / Programme delivery > Product & Technology ownership, governance > Agile delivery & tooling

OVERVIEW

I enjoy people and technology, process and strategy, especially when applied to smart business and meaningful services. This could be developing a product or enhancement, configuring a solution, eliciting and reflecting requirements, goals & constraints, helping design a great user experience and application flow, or simply helping others learn, enjoy & create. I love building, solving, and learning new things, but mostly enjoy working with and helping teams where we all grow, learn, and create great outcomes. Coffee?

EXPERIENCE

AskYourTeam - Senior Developer/Engineer

Apr 2022 - current (Full time, onsite and remote)

- Ruby on Rails, Rspec, AWS & DevOps, Good Job/async, React, BuildKite, Postgres RDS/DynamoDB, JSONB
- Feature leading, requirements, technical design, implementation, test coverage, deployment, pairing
- Product support, on-call duties, bug analysis and fix.
- Highlights: Org structure, imports, async/background job processing, Hubspot Integrations, Platform upgrades

Culture Amp - Analyst Developer Engineer "Performance Camp" - Scalability, Performance, Simplicity Focus Mar **2021** - Feb **2022** (Contract, 100% remote)

- Ruby on Rails, Rspec, AWS & DevOps, Sidekiq/async, React, Typescript, DataDog, BuildKite, RDS/Dynamo
- Uncoupling product areas from monolithic application and architecture (domain extraction). Microservices.
- Addressing technical debt, performance issues and common platform elements/issues across multiple teams
- Highlights: Shift exports async to RDS replica. Find/fix slow performing endpoints. Async and GDPR deletion.
 Technical debt and enhancements for UI/UX and API performance. Domain Driven Design platform rework.
 Monads. Patterns. React and Lambda integration with Launch Darkly SDKs and APIs.

Resn Digital - Technical Director - Development, Infrastructure, Integration & Operations Sept **2020** - Jan **2021** (Contract / Freelance)

- Technology investigation and solution design, scoping and sizing pre-sales, pre-development
- Development, Cloud Infrastructure & services admin, deployments and operations
- Scoping, sizing, infrastructure architecture for https://goodmeat.co, a Vue, ThreeJS & WebGL digital experience
- AWS S3, EC2, CloudFront, ACM, Lambda, Route53, AWS Organizations, IAM, Docker, Git, BitBucket pipelines
- Daily scrums, workflow management and kanban boards. Burn up/down tracking. Remote teams.
- Design and Operations documentation. Systems and Security audit and practices guide.

HireThings.com - Developer / CTO for application, platform & mobile-first upgrade (.co.nz / .com.au) Feb **2019** - Aug **2020** (Full time)

- Upgrade from Rails 2 to Rails 5. Shift and re-architect onto AWS platform services (Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Elasticache, S3, Route53, EC2, VPC / Security Groups, SES, IAM, Certs)
- Upgrade to mobile-first Bootstrap 4.5 front-end
- Product, business and UX improvements, Security patches and configuration
- Intern mentoring / training, code reviews, approvals and merges

Peter Torr Smith Profile - 2023

Ministry of Social Development IT - Web, Mobile, UX and Agile Technologies Manager May 2011 - Sept 2018 (Contract and full time)

- Business Analyst, Agile PM Ruby on Rails projects primarily. Web Team manager programme and project scoping, costing, delivery. Project pipeline coordinator - getting projects ready, scoped, approved
- RFP evaluation and vendor selection, contracts, liaison. Agile Toolsets Design and Operations SAFe, Atlassian Cloud Jira & Confluence
- Mobile & UX Capability Manager mixing internal and external capabilities. MyMSD, MyStudylink.

Catalyst IT - Business analyst / project manager / solution designer & dev / client liaison April **2009** - April **2011** (Full time)

- Client liaison, project scoping and solution design / options, RFPs, pre-sales
- Analyst / PM / co-dev for Drupal CMS, PHP, Moodle, and Ruby on Rails projects
- Facilitation, Testing, client support. TrueNet internal startup: UX & biz flow, web CMS build, logistics
- Development and solution configuration / operations

HireThings.com - Co-founder, CEO, CFO, Developer

April 2006 - May 2009 (Full time)

- Start-up co-founder, team support and HR. Developer, analyst, testing, ops Ruby on Rails / AJAX, UX, Wireframing, process design, solution co-design
- Summer of Tech (was Summer of Code) co-leadership

Intergen - Analyst developer and DBA - Microsoft technologies

April **2004** - April **2006** (Full time)

- Microsoft .Net developer (C#, ASP.net). SQL Server DBA, .Net/SAP API developer
- Onsite and offsite client technical support & development
- Web apps, Web Services, WinForms, Windows Services

eCentric - Analyst, Developer and DBA

Dec 2000 - Nov 2002 (Full time)

- Analyst Developer Delphi / .Net eCargo & dairy waste marketplaces. SQL Server DBA
- Early mobile-web (WAP) app design and development (XML and XSLT)
- Privilege & fun of working alongside founding Trade Me & AMR/Movac teams

Ministry of Agriculture (MAF) Jan 1994 - Sept 2000 (Full time) - Various business and technical roles

EDUCATION, TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT HIGHLIGHTS

Udemy - Ruby on Rails Professional - Re-learning Rails **2019**

- "Dissecting Ruby on Rails 5". Built ptorrsmith.com from scratch as a result. Prep for HireThings upgrade.
- Rails 5 (now 6), Javascript/JQuery, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, web-sockets, GIT and Heroku for hosting.

Enspiral Dev Academy - *Modern web and mobile development bootcamp* **Aug - Dec 2018** (Full time)

HTML5, CSS3 & CSS Frameworks, Javascript backend (node.js / Express) and front-end (React / Redux).
 Valuable human / soft / personal skills

Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) - foundation and in practice, - in-house and online 2016 - 2018

Enterprise application of SAFe with Jira, Confluence. Formal SAFe training, exams and certification 2017

MSP - Managing Successful Programs - Foundation and Professional 2015

Better Business Cases (BBC) - Training, Enterprise representation, and exam - Foundation 2013

PRINCE2 - 'Projects in Controlled Environments' - Foundation and Professional 2011

Certified Scrum Master - agile planning, delivery and team support **2011**

Microsoft Certified DBA - SQL Server DBA certification 2001 & 2006

Graduate Diploma - Information Sciences - Extramural and on-campus studies, Massey University **2001 Bachelor of Commerce,** University of Auckland - Management, Accounting, Economics, Marketing, Finance, Statistics, Business Computing

INTERESTS

Mobile, smart & connected technologies (IoT)
 Economics
 Fermentation
 Cooking
 Roasting coffee
 Swimming
 Hiking / walks
 Global social and tech/bio trends
 Campervanning
 Meditation, Mindfulness
 Predator Free NZ (volunteer)
 Helping others learn / mentoring

REFERENCES

On request